He'd do anything to get a great story.
Shattered Glass is a drama, history film directed by Billy Ray.
The true story of fraudulent Washington, D.C.
journalist Stephen Glass, who rose to meteoric heights as a young writer in his
20s, becoming a staff writer at The New Republic for three years.
Looking for a short cut to fame, Glass concocted sources, quotes and even entire stories, but his
deception did not go unnoticed forever, and eventually, his world came crumbling down.
Stephen Glass, played by Hayden Christensen.
Charles 'Chuck' Lane, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
Caitlin Avey, played by Chloë Sevigny.
Andy Fox, played by Rosario Dawson.
Amy Brand, played by Melanie Lynskey.
Michael Kelly, played by Hank Azaria.
Shattered Glass is a 2003 biographical drama film about journalist
Stephen Glass and his scandal at The New Republic.
Written and directed by Billy Ray in his feature directorial debut, the film
is based on a 1998 Vanity Fair article of the same name by H.
Bissinger and chronicles Glass' fall from grace when his
stories were discovered to be fabricated.
It stars Hayden Christensen as Glass, alongside Peter
Sarsgaard, Chloë Sevigny, and Steve Zahn.
The film premiered at the 2003 Toronto International Film Festival on September 10,
2003, and received a North American limited release on November 26, 2003.
Although a commercial failure, Shattered Glass received acclaim from critics, with
particular praise for Christensen and Sarsgaard's performances.
The tone is emotional.